Hi and welcome to this first Grand MA 3
tutorial there's a lot of tutorials
out there but i wanted to start over and make
the simplest form of tutorial that i could
based on just starting the console up for the
first time or the on pc version up for the first
time so basically what we want to do to get
started is to head over to malighting.com i
will drop a link down in the description below so
you can go in here and you can download the the
software so start here uh with the downloads click
that one go down to GrandMA 3 and click that one
and then you have software and release notes
down here so if you push this one you will go
down to the on pc versions there's two versions
now compared to the Grand MA 2 -  the GrandMA 2
Only had a windows version but GrandMA
3 comes for mac os and windows which is
really really great so depending on the operating
system you have download the correct version and
install it and when you have done that close
this one again you will have this icon up here
GrandMA 3 OnPC so if you double tap that one it
will start up the application for the first time
so basically what i want to do in this first
tutorial is just to make a brief run through
and and like tell you what what is where if
you compare to the real console the first
screen you are watching right here is is the same
as the screen number one over here on the on the
right console there's a few things missing down
here right now which is the encoder wheels and and
a lot of buttons and they they don't they don't
show up before you have patched uh a few fixtures
so right now it might look a little odd but
that is actually correct to navigate around
the console we have on the on the real console
you have on the full size version three major
screens three big screens right below that you
have three smaller screens and below that on the
on the surface surface itself you have two
small screens so if you wanna find those
screens in the on pc version you simply click
this button right here which is the screens
and this will show you screen one two and three
and this is one this is two and this is three
on the full size console then you have the
option of two external screens here external uh
which is screen output 4 and screen output 5 and
then you have the two small screens which you
can see here on the real console which doesn't
uh which shows up on the Grand MA 3 full size
console and the GrandMA 3 light console i don't
think it's on the smaller versions so basically
in the onpc version you can choose what you want
to see so you can open the screen you want to
see and want to work with but screens is not
all of it whoops up here if you push that button
this one up here that will open up the command
section where you do all your programming where
you have all your buttons your numeric keypad your
dimmers and where you save where you uh escape or
press oops or whatever this is all
hidden in in the under this button here
right below that one you have a fader section
which is like your master controls where you can
set your selected masters you can manipulate the
Grandmaster output the world master the highlight
the low light there's loads of different options
in here many of them i haven't really seen before
in the Grand MA 2 so some of it is new and
during this tutorial series we're going to look
at at most of it right below that one you have
your playback controls which is your basically
your your first fader bank section which
you will find over here on the real console
so when you start saving executors and manipulate
this this will show up in this in this area right
here and right below that one another master
section or custom master section as it is called
and this is also part of part of
the the desks what would you call it
default control that you can manipulate in here
you can set some rate masters rate masters, speed
masters and and stuff like that on the back side
of the rear side of the console you have a lot of
connectors that can do different things so
if we zoom in here you will see starting
from the left side you have your desk light
output you have your power input for your
powercon true1 you have your on and off switch
and then you have your six dmx outputs that is
the same amount of outputs as you had on the
Grand MA 2 and right next to that one is your dmx
dmx input which you can use right here and you
can confirm you can configure all of them to
be input or output that depends on whatever you
need to do so the versatility in the disk is is
pretty amazing right next to that you have
your midi in and outputs and right next to
that you have your time code input we will do a
separate tutorial on time code at a later point
on this channel you have your usbs everywhere
usb 2 and usb 3 and right next to that
you have your sound input which which you can
use if you need to do some sort of sound to light
to the right side you have your spdif in an
output and to the right again you have your three
ethernet ports on the Grand MA 2 you only had
two ethernet ports two separate network cards
on the GrandMA 3 you have three
separate networks card network cards
as my understanding right now is that only one and
two are active where one is your ma net and your
acn streaming acn and port number two is your ma
net i have heard rumors about port number three in
terms of ndi or citip or different
other protocols but i don't know if that's
that's the case yet at the top you have your
displayport outputs for your external screens
so you can connect up to two external screens
on the on the desk to give you more real estate
for your buttons and for all your folio stuff and
everything you want to to see when you open up the
console like this there's nothing in it this is
just a clean show so in the next episode we will
be patching a few fixtures and we will be looking
at different views and ways to manipulate them
so thank you for watching this episode and if you
find any value in this please like the video maybe
even subscribe to the channel that would that will
help us a lot and please if you have any questions
leave a comment down below so we can uh so we can
answer them uh as good as we can and that could
be suggestions for future tutorials so whatever
you need to uh to talk about so see you next time